Hello friends,
today we will talk about
which buttons we should keep in mind while buying health insurance
and in this video we
will discuss it completely and I will try to make you understand what all
things we have to
look at very carefully while
buying a policy. So let's start the video.
First of all you have to understand your needs.
Your family size
matters a lot because only according to them you
can choose your plan.
And according to family size, plans are
in different ranges and at different rates,
so you have to keep that thing in mind.
You have to choose a good plan according to your needs
which is within your budget. The
second TP is that you have to understand the features of the policy, the
minor things that are there. You have to
read their rules and
read all their details. You have to understand those
things. I have to see whether
your policy gives you cashless treatment or
not. Does it cover you for free existing diseases under the policy? Is its cost special or
not? You have to see that too. It is
very important for you to know all these things
because when you are buying this big policy.  If you will be able to know then
you will be able to buy a good policy, you will be
able to make a good plan, which will give you benefits in the future,
what is its process, it is
very important for you to know one thing, you have to keep in mind that
you should know whether the
policy you have bought
supports cashless or not,
if your policy
[Music]
Apart from this, one more thing to keep in mind is that from which
company you are
taking health insurance,
what is the claim ratio of that company
and how much time does it take to settle the claim, the
time period is
different for all the companies, so
you will have to keep that thing in mind while buying insurance,
one of the most important things is that from which company you are
buying the plan, how many hospitals are in panel with that company,
how many hospitals are
with the insurance company,
if there is a hospital near you, then you should
buy the plan of that company, otherwise you should
buy the plan of some other company
which is near your hospital,
so this is very important for you to know,
at the time of any emergency, if you
go to any nearby hospital, you will
find a hospital there  The
important thing is to understand, read, and discuss the terms of the policy you are
buying very closely. It is
very important to discuss it with the person you are buying from because from the beginning till the end, the
policy is handled by them. They will
keep you very close to the
policy terms at every point in your claim. So,
discuss everything with the person you buy the policy from before purchasing the policy.
Still, if you have any confusion regarding the policy,
you can talk to customer care and
get detailed information on this matter
or you can also get information by visiting the company's website.
Now, you must be asking
where to buy health insurance. And the question that
comes to everyone's mind is whether to buy it from an agent
or buy the policy online. Till now, if
you have faced any problem at the time of claim,
you can directly talk to
customer care. I have
not faced much problem in talking to customer care again and again.
This is my own experience.
Nowadays, there are many private
companies in the market and all of them have different plans. There is a
lot of competition, you have to choose between every plan.
You have to do things according to your family by comparing, in
which there are some plans, there is
individual health plan, there is family
floater and there is
also a plan for senior citizens, so this is common, apart from this there are
many plans running nowadays which you
can discuss with your agent,
while buying a policy, the budget matters a lot while buying any health policy
and the plan also matters a
lot, so you have to take some steps after considering both these things very
carefully and understanding them so
that you do
not face any problem in the future, so this is something
important which I have discussed with you
so that you do not face any problem in the future,
for such videos you can subscribe to our channel by
going to the comment section and commenting on it,
I will definitely reply to it, till then
thank you, watch this video till the
end and subscribe to the channel